Finding Aid for the Landon Cabell Garland Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
The Morris Frank Collection
undated
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0154
2.50 linear feet
- Correspondence, Outgoing
  - to Caroline M. Garland, July 22, 1927 (File 1)
  - to Spotswood Garland, December 4, 1830 (File 1)
  - to Samuel Garland, March 24, 1836 (File 1)
  - to Rev. John Early (Photostat Copy), December 16, 1839 (File 1)
  - to John Hampden Pleasants, June 1, 1846 (File 1)
  - to Caroline Garland, January 22, 1848 (File 1)
  - to Carolina Garland, December 1848 (File 1)
  - to Lucinda Rose Garland, April 17, 1849 (File 1)
  - to Lucinda Rose and Spotswood Garland, April 27, 1850 (File 1)
  - to Caroline Garland, July 17, 1857 (File 1)
  - to Caroline Garland, May 30, 1865 (File 1)
  - to J. R. Hale, February 8, 1993 (File 1)
  - Typed and Carbon copies of Garland Family Letters, 1829-1893 (File 2)
- Correspondence, Incoming
  - to L.C. Garland from Dr. F.A.P. Barnard, October 11, 1873 (File 3)
  - to L.C. Garland from Dr. F.A.P. Barnard, December 17, 1873 (File 3)
  - to L.C. Garland from W.G.E.Cummingham, May 25, 1873 (File 3)
  - to H.N. McTyeire from Prof. John Darby, September 11, 1873 (File 3)
  - to Lucinda Garland from Louise F. Garland, February 23, 1848 (File 3)
  - to Lucinda Garland from M.C. Garland, May 25, 1833 (File 3)
  - to Caroline Garland from Spotswood Garland, June 14, 1847 (File 3)
  - to L.C. Garland from Genealogical Society, January 3, 1973 (File 3)
  - to L.C. Garland from A.L.P. Green, February 1872 (File 3)
  - to L.C. Garland from A.L.P. Green, April 22, 1873 (File 3)
  - to L.C. Garland from A.L.P. Green, December 20, 1873 (File 3)
  - to L.C. Garland from A.L.P. Green, December 27, 1873 (File 3)
  - to H.N. McTyeire from J. Hamilton, July 4, 1873 (File 4)
  - to L.C. Garland from A. A. Lipscomb, October 9, 1879 (File 4)
  - to L.C. Garland from H.N. McTyeire, April 7, 1873 (File 4)
  - to L.C. Garland from H.N. McTyeire, March 17, 1873 (File 4)
  - to L.C. Garland from H.N. McTyeire, May 23, 1873 (File 4)
  - to L.C. Garland from H.N. McTyeire, June 21, 1873 (File 4)
  - to L.C. Garland from H.N. McTyeire, June 24, 1873 (File 4)
  - to L.C. Garland from H.N. McTyeire, July 22, 1873 (File 4)
  - to L.C. Garland from H.N. McTyeire, August 25, 1873 (File 4)
  - to L.C. Garland from H.N. McTyeire, September 13, 1873 (File 4)
  - to H.N. McTyeire from J.C. Granbery Enclosure, September 10, 1873 (File 4)
  - to L.C. Garland from H.N. McTyeire, November 13, 1873 (File 4)
  - to L.C. Garland from H.N. McTyeire, January 2, 1874 (File 5)
  - to L.C. Garland from H.N. McTyeire, January 17, 1874 (File 5)
  - to L.C. Garland from H.N. McTyeire, February 14, 1874 (File 5)
  - to L.C. Garland from H.N. McTyeire, February 28, 1874 (File 5)
  - to L.C. Garland from H.N. McTyeire, April 6, 1874 (File 5)
  - to L.C. Garland from H.N. McTyeire, April 15, 1874 (File 5)
  - to L.C. Garland from H.N. McTyeire, June 4, 1874 (File 5)
  - to L.C. Garland from H.N. McTyeire, September 3, 1874 (File 5)
  - to L.C. Garland from H.N. McTyeire, June 16, 1875 (File 6)
  - to L.C. Garland from H.N. McTyeire, July 13, 1875 (File 6)
  - to L.C. Garland from H.N. McTyeire, September 10, 1875 (File 6)
  - to L.C. Garland from John H. Rice, November 10, 1829 (File 6)
  - to L.C. Garland from Elliot F. Shepard, September 7, 1877 (File 6)
  - to L.C. Garland from J.H. Slaughter, July 17, 1879 (File 6)
  - to J.H. Slaughter from J. & T. Green Enclosure, February 13, 1877 (File 6)
  - to L.C. Garland from A.H. Sutherland, March 4, 1886 (File 6)
  - to L.C. Garland from D.S. Switzer, February 1873 (File 6)
  - to L.C. Garland from Joseph W. Taylor, March 26, 1874 (File 6)
  - to L.C. Garland from J.R. Tucker, July 1, 1893 (File 6)
  - to L.C. Garland from “A Well Wisher”, September 27, 1882 (File 6)
  - to Vanderbilt University from J.D. Eggleston, August 24, 1946 (File 7)
  - to J.D. Eggleston from Clara Mae Brown, September 21, 1946 (File 7)
  - to Mary Garland from Clara Mae Brown, September 21, 1946 (File 7)
  - to Clara Mae Brown from J.D. Eggleston, September 30, 1946 (File 7)
  - to Dr. Edwin Mims from Clara Mae Brown, October 4, 1946 (File 7)
  - to J.D. Eggleston from Clara Mae Brown, October 14, 1946 (File 7)
  - to Clara Mae Brown from Mary Garland, March 15, 1947 (File 7)
  - to Mary Garland from Clara Mae Brown, March 17, 1947 (File 7)
  - to J.D. Eggleston from Clara Mae Brown, March 17, 1947 (File 7)
  - to Clara Mae Brown from J.D. Eggleston, March 21, 1947 (File 7)
  - to Hampden-Sydney from Clara Mae Brown, April 10, 1958 (File 7)
  - to Clara Mae Brown from Paul L. Grier, April 14, 1958 (File 7)
  - to Paul L. Grier from Clara Mae Brown, April 21, 1958 (File 7)
- Diaries
  - 1880 (File 8)
  - 1882 (File 8)
- Writings, Speeches
  - to the Medical Students in Elm Street Methodist Church, December 5, 1880 (File 9)
  - to Vanderbilt University Medical Student Graduation, 1885 (File 9)
  - June 14, 1888 (File 9)
  - begins “This is altogether...”, Undated (File 9)
  - begins “In the first...”, Undated (File 9)
- Writings, Sermons
  - to the Faculty and Students of Vanderbilt University “ Truthfulness the Foundation of Character”, September 2,1883 (File 9)
- Writings, Reports
  - to the Board of Trust of Vanderbilt University, May 6, 1889 (File 9)
- Personal and Biographical Materials
  - Biographical Sketch-- L.C. Garland by Granddaughter Caroline Garland Lewis Montgomery (File 10)
  - Reminiscences-- February 12, 1895 Joseph M. Safford and O.E. Brown on the death of L.C. Garland (File 10)
  - Reminiscences-- October 11, 1943 H.H. White (File 10)
  - Articles-- Southern Dental Journal and Lumninary Vol. XV 1898 P. 304 (Photocopy--Refers to L.C. Garland’s early experiments with X-ray) (File 10)
  - Clippings-- The Comet and its Career (File 10)
  - Clippings-- American Postage Stamps (File 10)
  - Financial Records-- Loan Agreement from William Hagan (File 10)
  - Financial Records--Receipts (File 10)
    - for family’s board at M.W. College (Mississippi Weslyan College?), July 21, 1882
    - for butter, December 1, 1882
    - for Davidson County Taxes, December 4, 1882
  - Lists-- 1887 Books loaned to Dr. Barnard (File 10)
  - Ephemera-- Train Ticket (File 10)
  - Visiting Card from Fred F. Rose (File 10)
  - Printed directions for a Moehring Argand Burner (File 10)